Register of the Alfred M. Lilienthal papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1938-1995 (Boxes 31-68, 152-153)
  - "Palestinian-Israeli Co-Existence without Zionism," Speech, American Humanist Association, New York City. Handwritten notes, press release, and clipping, 14 November 1977. (Box-folder 49: 31)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Post, (date written). Typescript, 22 November 1977 (Box-folder 49: 32)
  - The Zionist Connection, 1978. See also CORRESPONDENCE, Christian Science Monitor and card file box 146 for readers' responses
    - Address list for book party (Box-folder 50: 1)
    - Comments (Box-folder 50: 2)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 50: 3-14)
    - Drafts. Typescript and carbon copies, and handwritten notes
      - Final version
        - Introduction (Box-folder 51: 1)
        - Chapter I (Box-folder 51: 2-4)
        - Chapter II (Box-folder 51: 5-6)
        - Chapter III (Box-folder 51: 7)
        - Chapter III (Box-folder 52: 1-4)
        - Chapters I, II, and III (fragments) (Box-folder 52: 5)
        - Chapter IV (Box-folder 52: 6-10)
        - Chapter V (Box-folder 53: 1-3)
        - Chapter VI (Box-folder 53: 4-8)
        - Chapter VII (Box-folder 54: 1-4)
        - Chapter VIII (Box-folder 54: 5-7)
        - Chapter VIII (Box-folder 55: 1)
        - Chapter IX (Box-folder 55: 2-3)
        - Chapter X (Box-folder 55: 4-6)
        - Chapter XI (Box-folder 56: 1)
        - Chapter XII (Box-folder 56: 2-3)
        - Chapter XIII (Box-folder 56: 4)
        - Chapter XIV (Box-folder 56: 5-7)
        - Chapter XV (Box-folder 57: 1)
        - Chapter XVI (Box-folder 57: 2)
        - Chapter XVII (Box-folder 57: 3)
        - Chapter XVIII (Box-folder 57: 4-5)
        - Chapter XIX (Box-folder 57: 6)
        - Chapter XX (Box-folder 57: 7)
        - Chapter XXI (Box-folder 57: 8)
        - Chapter XXII (Box-folder 58: 1)
        - Chapter XXIII (Box-folder 58: 2-3)
        - Chapter XXIV (Box-folder 58: 4)
        - Conclusion (Box-folder 58: 5-8)
        - Conclusion (Box-folder 59: 1-3)
        - Index (Box-folder 59: 4)
        - Quotations (Box-folder 59: 5)
      - Preliminary version
        - Outline (Box-folder 59: 6)
        - Chapter IV ("The Arab Image") (Box-folder 59: 7)
        - Chapter XXII ("The Arab World") (Box-folder 59: 8)
        - Chapter addendum 2 (Box-folder 59: 9)
        - Chapter addendum 3 (Box-folder 59: 10)
        - Chapter addendum 4 (Box-folder 59: 11)
        - Chapter addendum 6 (Box-folder 59: 12)
        - Chapter addendum 8 (Box-folder 59: 13)
        - Chapter addendum 10 (Box-folder 59: 14)
        - Quotes (Box-folder 59: 15)
      - Original "pre-73 war" draft (fragments) (Box-folder 60: 1)
    - Orders (Box-folder 60: 2)
    - Publicity material (Box-folder 60: 3-6)
    - Research material (Box-folder 60: 7-9)
    - Research material (Box-folder 61: 1-11)
    - Reviews. See also CORRESPONDENCE, National Catholic News Service (Box-folder 62: 1-3)
    - Summary (Box-folder 62: 4-6)
  - Interview by Philip Nobile, Sunday Magazine, Rockford, Printed copy, 7 January 1978. (Box-folder 63: 1)
  - Letter to the editor, Cleveland Press, (date written). Typescript, 9 January 1978 (Box-folder 63: 2)
  - Letter to the editor, Tribune (New York City), (date written). Typescript, 24 January 1978 (Box-folder 63: 3)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Typescript, 6 March 1978 (Box-folder 63: 4)
  - Open telegram to President Jimmy Carter, Press release, 12 March 1978. (Box-folder 63: 5)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Star, (date written). Typescript, 14 March 1978 (Box-folder 63: 6)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, Printed and typescript copies, 8 April 1978. (Box-folder 63: 7)
  - Letter to the editor, Boston Globe, Printed and typescript copies, 10 July 1978. (Box-folder 63: 8)
  - Letter to the editor, Sentinel Star, Printed and typescript copies, 25 July 1978. (Box-folder 63: 9)
  - Interview (Part I), Palestine, Printed copy, 15 August 1978. (Box-folder 63: 10)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Daily Press, (date written). Typescript, 28 August 1978 (Box-folder 63: 11)
  - Interview (Part II), Palestine, Printed copy, 31 August 1978. (Box-folder 63: 12)
  - Press conference, National Press Club, Washington, D.C., Press release, 31 August 1978. (Box-folder 63: 13)
  - Letter to the editor, Daily News, Printed and typescript copies, 28 September 1978. (Box-folder 63: 14)
  - Letter to the editor, Sentinel Star, (date written). Typescript, 9 November 1978 (Box-folder 63: 15)
  - Reply to WCBS editorial of Typescript, 20 September 1978, 21 November 1978. (Box-folder 63: 16)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Post Magazine, (date written). Typescript, 24 November 1978 (Box-folder 63: 17)
  - Statement, United Nations "International Day of Solidarity with the Palestinian People" press conference, Typescript. Includes suggested introduction of AML by Zehdi Labib Terzi, 29 November 1978. (Box-folder 63: 18)
  - "The Lessons of Iran: Will We Ever Learn?" Typescript, c. 1979. (Box-folder 63: 19)
  - Interview by press syndicate and press conference, WTJX TV, St. Thomas, Virgin Islands, 4 January 1979 (taped on 2 January). Printed copy, Daily News, 3 January 1979 (Box-folder 63: 20)
  - Letter to the editor, Daily News, Printed and typescript copies, 24 January 1979. (Box-folder 63: 21)
  - Interview, Colombian, Printed copy, 28 January 1979. (Box-folder 63: 22)
  - Letter to the editor, St. Croix Avis, Printed and typescript copies, 5 February 1979. (Box-folder 63: 23)
  - Reply to WINS commentary by Rabbi Tanenbaum on Typescript, 11 February 1979, 18 February 1979. (Box-folder 63: 24)
  - Letter to the editor, Colombus Dispatch, (date written). Typescript, 23 February 1979 (Box-folder 63: 25)
  - Press releases, Typescripts, 5 March 1979. (Box-folder 63: 26)
  - Speech, Holiday Inn, San Francisco, 16 March 1979. Printed copy of highlights, NAJDA Newsletter, May 1979 (Box-folder 63: 27)
  - Speech, San Francisco State University, San Francisco, California, Clippings, 19 March 1979. (Box-folder 63: 28)
  - Open telegram to Walter Mondale, Harry Byrd, and Howard Baker, Typescript, 21 March 1979. (Box-folder 63: 29)
  - "After Iran, Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, San Diego State University, San Diego, California. Correspondence and clippings, 22 March 1979. (Box-folder 63: 30)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times Magazine, Printed and typescript copies, and letter to Barbara Dubivsky, 25 March 1979. (Box-folder 63: 31)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, American School of International Management, Glendale, Arizona. Clippings, 26 March 1979. (Box-folder 63: 32)
  - "What Price Middle East Peace?" Speech, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona. Clippings, 28 March 1979. (Box-folder 63: 33)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, St. George's Church, Houston, Texas. Clippings, 6 April 1979. (Box-folder 63: 34)
  - "The Mideast Peace Treaty," Arizona Daily Star, Printed copy, 8 April 1979. (Box-folder 63: 35)
  - "Now that Treaty Is Signed ... Has Palestinian Fuse Been Lit?" San Diego Union, Printed copy, 8 April 1979. (Box-folder 63: 36)
  - Letter to the editor, U.S. News and World Report, (date written). Typescript, 9 April 1979 (Box-folder 63: 37)
  - "After Iran: Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, School of Politics, Women's National Republican Club, New York City. Press release and correspondence, 11 April 1979. (Box-folder 63: 38)
  - Radio appearance, Larry King Show, Mutual Broadcasting System, Arlington, Virginia, Handwritten notes and correspondence with Larry King, Gip Oldham, and others, 14 April 1979. (Box-folder 63: 39)
  - Letter to the editor, San Diego Union, (date written). Typescript, 23 April 1979 (Box-folder 63: 40)
  - "Violence, Oil, and Middle East War," Speech, New York State University, New Paltz, New York. Press release and correspondence, 1 May 1979. (Box-folder 63: 41)
  - Reply to WCBS editorial of Typescript, 26 March 1979, 3 May 1979. (Box-folder 63: 42)
  - "The Zionist Connection: What Price Peace?" Speech, Moorehead State University, Moorehead, Minnesota. Press release and clipping, 14 May 1979. (Box-folder 63: 43)
  - "There Goes the Middle East," Speech, Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio. Handwritten notes, correspondence, and clipping, 15 May 1979. (Box-folder 63: 44)
  - Interview, Ohio State Lantern, Printed copy, 18 May 1979. (Box-folder 63: 45)
  - Radio appearance, David Gold Show, WITS, Boston, Massachusetts, Correspondence, 10 June 1979. (Box-folder 63: 46)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech and panel discussion, 18th Annual Unitarian-Universalist Assembly, Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan. Printed and typescript copies, correspondence, and press release, 27 June 1979. (Box-folder 63: 47)
  - Reply to WCBS editorials of (date written). Typescript letter, 16-17 and 23-24 August 1979, 24 September 1979 (Box-folder 63: 48)
  - "The Zionist Connection Reviewed," America, Printed copy, typescript (originally entitled "What Price Repression?"), and correspondence with Joseph O'Hare, 6 October 1979. (Box-folder 63: 49)
  - "What Price Israel?" Speech, University of Delaware, Newark, Delaware. Handwritten notes, clipping, press release, and correspondence with Robert W. Andrews, 31 October 1979. (Box-folder 63: 50)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Typescript, 10 November 1979 (Box-folder 63: 51)
  - "What Price Peace in the Middle East?" Speech, Dalhousie University, Halifax, Canada. Handwritten notes, clippings, and correspondence with Ismail Zayid, 13 November 1979. (Box-folder 63: 52)
  - Letter to the editor, Dartmouth Free Press, (date written). Typescript, 26 November 1979 (Box-folder 63: 53)
  - Draft letter to presidential aspirants, Typescript, 1980. (Box-folder 64: 1)
  - Testimony, "Blue Ribbon" Middle East panel, National Council of Churches, New York City, Typescript, press release, and correspondence. Includes statement by the Palestine Congress of North America, 6 February 1980. (Box-folder 64: 2)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Typescript, 21 February 1980 (Box-folder 64: 3)
  - "Why not a Palestinian State?" Speech, College of Virgin Islands, St. Croix, Virgin Islands. Announcement and clippings, 4 March 1980. (Box-folder 64: 4)
  - Letter to the editor, Newsweek, (date written). Typescript, 10 March 1980 (Box-folder 64: 5)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Star, (date written). Typescript, 21 March 1980 (Box-folder 64: 6)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, New Jersey. Press release, clippings, and correspondence, 26 March 1980. (Box-folder 64: 7)
  - "The Middle East: Friend or Foe?" Speech, Syracuse University, Syracuse, New York. Correspondence, 28 March 1980. (Box-folder 64: 8)
  - Interview by Janet Langhart, WMCA Radio, New York City, Handwritten notes, 2 April 1980. (Box-folder 64: 9)
  - "The Zionist Connection and How it Affects You," Speech, Southport Congregational Church, Southport, Connecticut. Press release and correspondence, 3 April 1980. (Box-folder 64: 10)
  - Reply to WINS commentary by Rabbi Tannenbaum, Typescript and letter to WINS executive director Joe Gillespie, 2-3 May 1980. (Box-folder 64: 11)
  - Interview, al-Dustour, Printed copy (in Arabic) and typescript translation, 26 May 1980. (Box-folder 64: 12)
  - Letter to the editor, The Times, (date written). Typescript and handwritten draft, 31 May 1980 (Box-folder 64: 13)
  - "Zionism and American Jews," Arab Perspectives, June 1980, and The Journal of Historical Review, Printed copies (Box-folder 64: 14)
  - Letter to the editor, La Presse, L'Action, and al-Sabah, (date written). Typescript copies, 2 July 1980 (Box-folder 64: 15)
  - "Palestine, the 1980 Captive Nation," 20 July 1980. Speech, "Captive Nations Day," Sherwood Inn, Epsom, New Hampshire. Handwritten notes and clippings. Includes mailgram of 26 August 1980 to William Loeb, publisher of the Union Leader, re his editorial of, 25 July 1980 (Box-folder 64: 16)
  - Interview by Pia Lindstrom, "Live at Five," NBC, New York City, Typescript excerpts, 23 September 1980. (Box-folder 64: 17)
  - Interview, Spotlight, Printed copy, 27 October 1980. (Box-folder 64: 18)
  - "A Positive Middle East Policy," Speech, Council for the Advancement of Arab-British Understanding, Westminster Hall, London, England. Press release, 28 October 1980. (Box-folder 64: 19)
  - "The Right of Self-Determination: Why not the Palestinians?" Conference paper, International Progress Organization Conference on Palestine, Vienna, Austria, 5-7 November 1980.
    - Typescript drafts (Box-folder 64: 20)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 64: 21)
    - Proceedings (Box-folder 64: 22)
  - Press release, Typescript, 17 November 1980. (Box-folder 64: 23)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, Library Associates, University Club, Washington, D.C. Printed copy, typescript, press release, and correspondence. Includes typescript copy of introduction of AML, 19 November 1980. (Box-folder 64: 24)
  - Debate with Martin Abend, Women's National Republican Club, New York City, Correspondence, 2 December 1980. (Box-folder 65: 1)
  - Press release, Typescript, 15 December 1980. (Box-folder 65: 2)
  - Letter to the editor, Jerusalem Post, (date written). Typescript, 17 December 1980 (Box-folder 65: 3)
  - Press release, Typescript, 12 January 1981. (Box-folder 65: 4)
  - Letter to the editor, Seattle Times, (date written). Typescript, 19 January 1981 (Box-folder 65: 5)
  - Open letter to President Ronald Reagan, Press release, 20 January 1981. (Box-folder 65: 6)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, Ohio University, Athens, Ohio. Correspondence with Issam M. Hamadeh (Ohio University Palestine Club). Includes the by-laws of the O.U.P.C., 12 February 1981. (Box-folder 65: 7)
  - Press release on Stephen J. Solarz, Typescript, 27 February 1981. (Box-folder 65: 8)
  - "U.S. Policy: Good or Bad for the U.S.?" Speech, Dutch Treat Club, New York City. Correspondence with Lowell Thomas, 17 March 1981. (Box-folder 65: 9)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, Iowa State University, Ames, Iowa. Press release, clipping, and correspondence, 3 May 1981. (Box-folder 65: 10)
  - Open letter to the people of the Virgin Islands, Daily News, St. Thomas, Typescript and correspondence, 7 May 1981. (Box-folder 65: 11)
  - Letter to the editor, US News and World Report, (date written). Typescript, 11 May 1981 (Box-folder 65: 12)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, Canadians for Justice in the Middle East, Windsor Hotel, Montreal, Canada. Press release, clipping, and correspondence, 15 May 1981. (Box-folder 65: 13)
  - Letter to the editor, Commentary, (date written). Typescript, 20 May 1981 (Box-folder 65: 14)
  - Speech, The Secretary's Open Forum, U.S. Department of State, Washington, D.C., Typescript and correspondence with George S. Dragnich, 3 June 1981. (Box-folder 65: 15)
  - "Semite and Anti-Semite: A Confusion Stifling American Freedom," Speech, Holy Land State Conference, Washington Marriott Hotel, Washington, D.C. Typescript, press release, program, and clipping, 27 June 1981. (Box-folder 65: 16)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Typescript, 30 August 1981 (Box-folder 65: 17)
  - Comments after Evan G. Galbraith lunch, Women's National Republican Club, Washington, D.C., Typescript, 5 October 1981. (Box-folder 65: 18)
  - Reply to WCBS editorial of Printed and typescript copies, correspondence, and memorandum regarding the broadcast of AML's reply, 8-9 October 1981, 16-17 October 1981. (Box-folder 65: 19)
  - Debate with Stephen Solarz, "What's the Point?" WNYM Radio, Staten Island, New York, (scheduled date; debate was cancelled when Solarz changed his mind about appearing). Typescript list of questions, 26 October 1981 (Box-folder 65: 20)
  - Informal talk, City Council, Dundee, Scotland, Typescript account, clippings, and correspondence, 17 November 1981. (Box-folder 65: 21)
  - "Breaches of International Law and our Communications Systems," Statement, Baghdad International Seminar on the Legal Effects of Attacking Iraqi Nuclear Installations and the Right to Peaceful Uses of Atomic Energy, Baghdad, Iraq. Printed copy, 29 November 1981. (Box-folder 65: 22)
  - Reply to Channel 2 editorial, Typescript, December 1981. (Box-folder 65: 23)
  - "How Can American Public Opinion Be Captured?" Speech, al-Najah University, Nablus, West Bank. Typescript, 7 December 1981. (Box-folder 65: 24)
  - Interview by Mona el-Said, Monday Morning, Printed copy, 14-20 December 1981. (Box-folder 65: 25)
  - The Zionist Connection II: What Price Peace?, 1982
    - English edition, 1982
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 65: 26)
      - Draft of new chapter and last words (Box-folder 65: 27)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 65: 28)
      - Publicity material (Box-folder 65: 29)
      - Reviews (Box-folder 65: 30)
    - Czech and Eastern European edition, 1985-1988
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 65: 31)
      - Draft of last words (updated) (Box-folder 65: 32)
      - Reviews (Box-folder 65: 33)
  - "A New U.S. Middle East Policy: Our Crying Need," Speech, Stetson University, Deland, Florida. Press release, clipping, and correspondence, 6 January 1982. (Box-folder 66: 1)
  - Press release, Typescript, 12 January 1982. (Box-folder 66: 2)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Post, (date written). Typescript, 20 January 1982 (Box-folder 66: 3)
  - Letter to the editor, Post (West Palm Beach), (date written). Typescript, 2 February 1982 (Box-folder 66: 4)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Typescript, 13 February 1982 (Box-folder 66: 5)
  - Eulogy of Moshe Menuhin, New York Times, Printed copy, 14 February 1982. (Box-folder 66: 6)
  - Press release, Typescript, March 1982. (Box-folder 66: 7)
  - Statement relative to the lawsuit over the bequest of the Palestine Liberation Organization, Typescript, 5 March 1982. (Box-folder 66: 8)
  - "What Price Middle East Peace?" Speech, Princeton University Graduate School, Princeton, New Jersey. Press release, correspondence, and handwritten notes (also used for speech of 25 May 1982, and possibly also in November 1981 in Scotland). Includes account of speech by Peter Coveney, 10 March 1982. (Box-folder 66: 9)
  - Letter to the editor, Daily News, 20 March 1982, and San Juan Star, Printed copies. See also CORRESPONDENCE, Rotary Club. Includes notes on AML's trip to St. Thomas, Virgin Islands, March 1982, 6 April 1982. (Box-folder 66: 10)
  - Letter to the editor, Lowell Sun, Printed copy, 30 March 1982. (Box-folder 66: 11)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Typescript, 10 April 1982 (Box-folder 66: 12)
  - "There Positively Goes the Middle East," Speech, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, New Jersey. Press release and correspondence, 29 April 1982. (Box-folder 66: 13)
  - Press release, Typescript, 30 April 1982. (Box-folder 66: 14)
  - Letter to the editor, San Juan Star, (date written). Typescript, 7 May 1982 (Box-folder 66: 15)
  - "Zionist Connection," Speech, Delta College, University City, Michigan. Correspondence and press release, 18 May 1982. (Box-folder 66: 16)
  - "There Goes the Middle East," Speech, Canadians for Justice in the Middle East, Ottawa, Canada. Press release and correspondence. See also 10 March 1982, 25 May 1982. (Box-folder 66: 17)
  - Appearance on Newsmakers, WTMJ, Milwaukee, Letter from Kathleen Dumm, June 1982. (Box-folder 66: 18)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Typescript, 6 September 1982 (Box-folder 66: 19)
  - Letter to the editor, Honolulu Star Bulletin, (date written). Typescript, 21 September 1982 (Box-folder 66: 20)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, 19 October 1982 (date written). Typescript. Also sent to America (Box-folder 66: 21)
  - "Israel's Flag Is still not Mine," Typescript and correspondence, November 1982. (Box-folder 66: 22)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Post, (date written). Typescript, 22 November 1982 (Box-folder 66: 23)
  - "What Kind of an Israel?" Middle East Perspective, February 1983. Typescript of editorial. Includes printed copy, U.S. Farm News, August 1984 (Box-folder 66: 24)
  - Letter to the editor, Minnesota Daily, (date written). Typescript, 3 February 1983 (Box-folder 66: 25)
  - "There Goes the Middle East," Speech, Arizona State University, Phoenix, Arizona. Press release and clipping, 3 February 1983. (Box-folder 66: 26)
  - "U.S. Middle East Foreign Policy: Good or Bad?" 7 February 1983. Speech, American Graduate School of International Management, Glendale, Arizona. Printed copy of a letter to the editor, Das Tor, by Laura E. Chatfield, 2 March 1983 (Box-folder 66: 27)
  - Press conference, Student Union, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona, Clipping, 9 February 1983. (Box-folder 66: 28)
  - "Where Goes the Middle East?" Speech, University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona. Clipping, 10 February 1983. (Box-folder 66: 29)
  - "The Role of Peacekeeping Forces in the Middle East," Speech, United Nations Association, Monterey Institute of International Studies, Monterey, California. Press release and correspondence with Betty Anne Sherif, 14 February 1983. (Box-folder 66: 30)
  - "Einstein and Israel: A Reply to Morton Ryweck," Minnesota Daily, 17 February 1983. Printed copy and a subsequent letter to the editor by a reader. Includes an article by Thomas N. Dikel, Minnesota Daily, mentioning AML's article, 24 February 1983 (Box-folder 66: 31)
  - "There Goes the Middle East," Speech, Oregon State University, Corvallis, Oregon. Press release and correspondence, 18 February 1983. (Box-folder 66: 32)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times, (date written). Typescript, 10 March 1983 (Box-folder 66: 33)
  - Letter to the editor, Chicago Tribune, (date written). Typescript, 11 April 1983 (Box-folder 66: 34)
  - Letter to the editor, Boston Globe, (date written). Typescript, 11 April 1983 (Box-folder 66: 35)
  - "Hussein Cannot Represent Palestinians," USA Today, Printed copy, 11 April 1983. (Box-folder 66: 36)
  - Letter to the editor, Daily News, (date written). Typescript, 13 April 1983 (Box-folder 66: 37)
  - "Repression Must Lead Inevitably to Tragedy," USA Today, Printed copy, 19 April 1983. (Box-folder 66: 38)
  - Letter to the editor, New York Times Magazine, (date written). Typescript, 30 June 1983 (Box-folder 66: 39)
  - Remarks, European Regional Preparatory Meeting of the International Conference on the Question of Palestine, Geneva, Switzerland, 4-8 July 1983. Typescript copies, clipping, and correspondence. Includes statements of other participants, 6 July 1983 (Box-folder 66: 40-41)
  - Letter to the editor, International Herald Tribune, (date written). Typescript, 19 July 1983 (Box-folder 66: 42)
  - "The Realities of Public Opinion in North America (with Special Emphasis on the United States) and Middle East Peace," Conference paper, International Conference on the Question of Palestine, Geneva, Switzerland, 29 August-7 September 1983. Typescript, handwritten notes, and correspondence. Includes papers by other participants, 5 September 1983. (Box-folder 67: 1)
  - "The Middle East: Our New Vietnam?" Speech, American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee, Adam's Mark Hotel, Houston, Texas. Press release and correspondence with Ellen M. Mansoor, 30 September 1983. (Box-folder 67: 2)
  - Letter to the editor, USA Today, (date written). Typescript, 23 October 1983 (Box-folder 67: 3)
  - "The Middle East: Our New Vietnam?" Speech, Pennsylvania State University, University Park, Pennsylvania. Press release, clippings, and correspondence, 2 November 1983. (Box-folder 67: 4)
  - Interview by J. Mark Brady and G. A. Selgin, Libertarian Broadside, Printed copy, 21 November 1983. (Box-folder 67: 5)